Connecticut Soldiers Collection
© 2005 University of Connecticut
Connecticut Soldiers Collection, Linwood Aldrich Papers.
undated, 1943-1944.
Archives & Special Collections at the Thomas J. Dodd Research Center.
Aldrich, Linwood.
1.25 linear feet.
The collection contains correspondence from Linwood Aldrich to his wife, Esther Aldrich, between 1943 and 1944.
MSS20020027
Biography
Linwood and Esther Aldrich lived in Norwich, Connecticut. Married in September 1942, Linwood Aldrich worked for the Thermos Bottle Company as a sealer and Esther was employed at the Lee and Osgood Company as a stenographer. At the time the correspondence begins in July 1943, Linwood (882nd Signal Co.) is based in New Orleans, Louisiana. In August, he transfers to the HQ Detachment, also in New Orleans. The Detachment is shipped out to England in November, only days before he was scheduled to have his first leave to visit home since entering the service. The last two months of the correspondence in the collection indicates that Aldrich was transferred to France in November 1944. The correspondence ends a month later.
Research in the Norwich City Directory documents that the Aldrichs were reunited by 1947 and continued to live at the same address for many years before moving to the East Great Plain section of Norwich in the mid 1950s. Linwood continued to work for Thermos until his retirement around 1977.
Scope and Content
The collection contains correspondence from Linwood Aldrich to his wife, Esther, from July 1943 through December 1944. The correspondence documents the interests, concerns and activities of these two Connecticut residents during wartime while Aldrich was stationed in the United States and abroad.
Arrangement
Series I: Correspondence ( undated, 1943-1944 ) contains correspondence from Linwood Aldrich to his wife, Esther, while he was stationed in Louisiana and England during World War II.
Related Material
Archives & Special Collections has a substantial collection of materials pertaining to Connecticut history, especially correspondence or diaries of Connecticut veterans during wartime. See especially, Connecticut Soldiers Collection and the Thermos Company Collection. For detailed information on these collections please contact the curator or ask at the reference desk.
Separated Material
The following materials have been separated from the collection and are housed separately:
Two small black and white snapshots taken in England in 1944.
Index Terms
This record series is indexed under the following controlled access subject terms.
Persons:
Aldrich, Linwood.
Places:
Norwich (Conn.)
Subjects:
Soldiers--Connecticut--Correspondence.; World War, 1939-1945--Personal narratives--Connecticut.; Norwich (Conn.)--Family and personal papers.; Connecticut--Family and personal papers.
Document Types:
Correspondence.; Photographs.
Restrictions on Access
There are no access restrictions on this collection.
Acquisition Information
The collection was acquired from Charles Apfelbaum in 2002.
Detailed Description
- Series I: Correspondence, undated, 1943-1944
  - undated (Box 1:, Folder 1)
  - 1943 July (Box 1:, Folder 2)
  - 1943 August 1 - 9 (Box 1:, Folder 3)
  - 1943 August 10 - 20 (Box 1:, Folder 4)
  - 1943 August 21 - 31 (Box 1:, Folder 5)
  - 1943 September 1 - 10 (Box 1:, Folder 6)
  - 1943 September 11 - 20 (Box 1:, Folder 7)
  - 1943 September 21 - 30 (Box 1:, Folder 8)
  - 1943 October (Box 1:, Folder 9)
  - 1943 November (Box 1:, Folder 10)
  - 1943 December (Box 1:, Folder 11)
  - 1944 January 1 - 15 (Box 1:, Folder 12)
  - 1944 January 16 - 31 (Box 1:, Folder 13)
  - 1944 February (Box 2:, Folder 14)
  - 1944 March (Box 2:, Folder 15)
  - 1944 April (Box 2:, Folder 16)
  - 1944 May (Box 2:, Folder 17)
  - 1944 June (Box 2:, Folder 18)
  - 194e July (Box 2:, Folder 19)
  - 1944 August (Box 2:, Folder 20)
  - 1944 September (Box 2:, Folder 21)
  - 1944 October (Box 3:, Folder 22)
  - 1944 November (Box 3:, Folder 23)
  - 1944 December (Box 3:, Folder 24)